The Count of Monte-Cristo is a adventure, drama, tv
movie film directed by David Greene.
A TV adaptation of the classic Alexandre Dumas novel.
Edmond Dantes is falsely accused by those jealous of his good fortune, and is sentenced to
spend the rest of his life in the notorious island prison, Chateau d'If.
While imprisoned, he meets the Abbe Faria, a fellow
prisoner whom everyone believes to be mad.
The Abbe tells Edmond of a fantastic treasure hidden away on a
tiny island, that only he knows the location of.
After many years in prison, the old Abbe dies, and
Edmond escapes disguised as the dead body.
Now free, Edmond must find the treasure the Abbe told him of, so he can use the
new-found wealth to exact revenge on those who have wronged him.
Edmond Dantès, played by Richard Chamberlain.
Abbé Faria, played by Trevor Howard.
Villefort, played by Louis Jourdan.
Danglars, played by Donald Pleasence.
Fernand Morcerf Mondego, played by Tony Curtis.
Mercédès, played by Kate Nelligan.
The Count of Monte Cristo is a 1975 television film produced by ITC Entertainment and
based upon the 1844 novel The Count of Monte Cristo by Alexandre Dumas.
Like the novel, The film emphasizes the theme of revenge and
manipulation of characters by the main character, Edmond Dantès.
The film was directed by David Greene and stars Richard Chamberlain as Edmond Dantès, Kate Nelligan as Mercedes, Tony Curtis as Fernand Mondego, Louis Jourdan (who played
Dantès in the 1961 film adaptation of the novel) as De Villefort, Donald Pleasence as Danglars, Trevor Howard as Abbé Faria, and Isabelle de Valvert as Haydee.
ITC had previously produced a 39-part TV series based on the
same source material and broadcast in 1956.
This film had a theatrical release across some European countries.
The film was remade in 1986 in Telugu as Veta.
The film explores themes of treasure, based on novel or
book, falsely accused, return, revenge.
The tone is emotional.